Chashmeet Singh

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

641-4 Albert Street, Waterloo, ON, N2L 3V5

☐ (365) 228-1703 🔀 singh1sy@uwindsor.ca 🛊 🖶 www.chashmeet.com 🖟 chashmeetsingh 📗 chashmeet

Summary

- 4+ years experience as a Full Stack Freelance Developer in developing web and mobile applications
- Open Source Software Developer and maintainer of several repositories
- · Interested in solving challeging tasks in an Agile and fast learning environment
- · Regular participant of local hackathons and technical meetups events

Technical Skills

Programming Languages / Frameworks: Swift/iOS, Ruby on Rails, C/C++, Java/Android, Python/Django, Apex/

Salesforce, C#, Phoenix, PHP, Objective C Operating Systems: Unix, Linux, Windows

Software Applications: XCode, VSCode, Android Studio, Sketch, Rubymine, WebStorm

Databases: SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, PL/SQL, MongoDB

Education

Master of Applied Computing

Windsor, ON

University of Windsor

Sep. 2018 - Apr 2020

B.Tech. Computer Science and Engineering

Aug. 2014 - Jul. 2018

New Delhi, India

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

Work Experience

BlackBerry Ltd. Waterloo, ON

Salesforce Software Development Student

Sept. 2019 - Present

- Developed several Salesforce community Lightning Web Components(LWC) by working on both backend and frontend
- Helped decommission several components to improve page performance and customer experience

Venturit Inc. Windsor, ON (Remote)

Application Developer

Jul. 2019 - Present

- · Worked on a Ruby on Rails Web Application developing various features and working on both backend and frontend
- · Collaborated with a team of 6 members across the globe with regular scrum meetings and feature demos

SiliconBrane Inc. Windsor, ON

Mobile App Developer

Nov. 2018 - Apr 2019

- Built an iOS app to receive and process data from IoT device using LoRa such as qps, device battery and direction
- Created an algorithm to display location of the pet for the last week based on the current zoom

Google Summer of Code Intern (FOSSASIA)

Singapore (Remote)

iOS Developer Intern

May. 2017 - Sep. 2017

- Collaborated with a team of 10+ developers across the globe to develop and test the implementation of new features
- Presented weekly updates through demonstrations to other team members over Google Hangouts and scrum meeting
- Held workshops in Delhi to promote open source software and taught usage of basic software development tools

Udacity Inc. Mountain View, CA (Remote)

Mentor / Reviewer Nov. 2016 - Aug. 2017

- Mentored students across the world in problem solving and suggesting efficient ways of implementation
- Reviewed projects of several students by providing quality feedback on the code structures and design

NXT Sports LLC Chicago, PA (Remote)

Rails / iOS Contract Developer Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2017 Collaborated with a team of 6 people remotely across the world to develop the Web Application and the API

- Developed the iOS Application from scratch up within a span of two months by making use of the backend APIs

Nov 18 2019 CHASHMEET SINGH

Projects

FoodCourt (Team Project)

University of Windsor, Windsor, ON

Sep. 2018 - Nov. 2018

Tech Stack: Swift, Cocoapods, iOS, AutoLayout, Java, Springboot, REST API

- iOS app to enable users to buy products from multiple outlets in a food court in a single transaction.
- Integrated authentication from OAuth libraries such as Google and Facebook.
- Developed Guest Mode to enable users to navigate through the app without signing up for it
- · Implemented Vendor side with listing orders dynamically from the server which gets updated automatically.

SUSI.AI iOS (Individual Project)

Mar. 2017 - Present

Tech Stack: Swift, Cocoapods, iOS, AutoLayout, Realm, Objective C, Java

- Designed a bot chat interface with the ability to show different types of messages like video, audio, maps, etc.
- Developed handsfree mode to enable the user to interact using hotword recognition similar to Siri or Ok Google.
- Built a feedback system to enable users to help improve the responses by the AI server.

GPS Info Alarm (Individual Project)

March 2018

Tech Stack: Swift, iOS, Cocoapods, AutoLayout, Realm

- Developed an app for a client to get GPS device alerts and alarms
- Integrated Google Maps and Places API to get the current location of those devices through alerts.

TrackMyShows (Team Project)

Sep. 2015 - Dec. 2016

Tech Stack: Android, Realm, Ruby on Rails, Java, SQLite, REST API

- Worked with Android to build the functionality to authenticate and locally save data of tv shows.
- Implemented the backend server to provide combined data to the android app from various other APIs.
- Designed the logic to provide synchronization between several devices owned by the user.
- After maintaining a successful 1k+ users daily and over 50k installs within 6 months, the app was sold for USD 2500.

Weekender (Team Project)

Apr 2016

Tech Stack: Android, Ruby on Rails, Java, SQLite, REST API

- Built at Yatra Hackathon within a period of 16 hours with fully functional API
- · Worked on the backend API to suggest nearby places for planning a trip with recommendations to places of visit

Honors and Activities

Mentor at Codementor.io	Oct 2015 - Present
Best Implementation of Security Measures - Hack Western V	Nov 2018
Mentor at Google Summer of Code	May 2018 - Aug 2018
Mentor at Google Code In	2017, 2018
Winner of Fastest Startup Time - Droidcon UK App, London	Nov 2016
Runner's Up - PayUMoney Hackathon	Sept 2015
Programming SIG Head	Feb 2015 - Jun 2015
Event Co-ordinator - Avensis (Annual College Techfest)	Sept 2014

Technical Training

React.JS Essential Training	May 2019
IBM Cloud Essentials	Nov 2018
iOS Developer Nanodegree - Udacity	Sept 2016
Introduction to Linux - edX	Feb 2015
Introduction to Computer Science Using Python	Oct 2014
Introduction to Computer Programming	Sept 2014

Nov 18, 2019 CHASHMEET SINGH 2